{
    "id": "8f3e195978b7463fbed833749fb063db",
    "title": "Common English Structures",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I would rather consult a doctor than ................................ in fear.",
            "description": "Would rather is followed by an infinitive without to. ",
            "answers": [
                "live",
                "to live",
                "living"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c67a81cb52da4711ad307faa8afc3d74"
        },
        {
            "question": "I can't help ................................... about her.",
            "description": "If you say that you can’t help doing something, you mean that you can’t stop yourself from doing it. \r\nIn this structure we use an ing form after help.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "to worry",
                "worrying",
                "worry"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a07b1093192b45bf9848a050e0cf6a3c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I couldn't help ................................... those cookies.",
            "description": "If you say that you can’t help doing something, you mean that you can’t stop yourself from doing it. \r\nIn this structure we use an ing form after help.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "eating",
                "to eat"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "653383185d6e49bfa994bc43d87357cb"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is busy ................................. ready for work.",
            "description": "The structure I am busy is followed by an –ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to get",
                "getting",
                "with getting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c460eb8eeb43421ab86a19fbe639b749"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am busy .................................... the house.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to clean",
                "cleaning",
                "to cleaning"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f40225b6ace348faaeb40a5fb7cc121a"
        },
        {
            "question": "Brother is busy ...................................... his studies.",
            "description": "Instead of an –ing form, we can use with + noun after I’m busy.",
            "answers": [
                "with",
                "from",
                "of"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4f46f5c716894a35a9fe9524fa4fec04"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am looking forward .................................. Paris.",
            "description": "Look forward to / Looking forward to is followed by an ing form or a noun.",
            "answers": [
                "to visit",
                "visiting",
                "to visiting"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "66a47aba175a4cdf9a2a38f3d129aa1e"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will help you ....................................... the cleaning.",
            "description": "Before a noun we use help with.",
            "answers": [
                "with",
                "about",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "651778a959174dc0b1be7fb0f641ce8e"
        },
        {
            "question": "Can you help me ....................................... my keys?",
            "description": "Help can be followed by object + infinitive with or without to.",
            "answers": [
                "find",
                "to find",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "fb592791b5994f51bb931ddf7b65af3a"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is your turn .................................... the dishes.",
            "description": "An infinitive with to is used in this structure.",
            "answers": [
                "doing",
                "to do",
                "to doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "02fb15b0122e474d831acfa481a58988"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am having a hard time ..................................... a good job.",
            "description": "An ing form is used in this structure.",
            "answers": [
                "to find",
                "finding",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8a9e762d0d3c4c0b975948cef005b5d1"
        },
        {
            "question": "You had better ..................................... me my money back.",
            "description": "After had better the infinitive is used without to. ",
            "answers": [
                "to give",
                "give",
                "to giving"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "da67ec6393fd4b8baa6fe29654047104"
        }
    ]
}